<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ARG@ENU</title>
    <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on ARG@ENU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 14:58:11 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://arg.napier.ac.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Poster Presentation on Argument Visualisation at Scale</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.06.23_eca_dana/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 14:58:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.06.23_eca_dana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dana Khartabil presented a poster at the Second European Conference on Argumentation based upon her Ph.D research. Briefly, we are interested in the tools that are needed to usefully explore increasingly larger datasets of analysed argumentation, whether this comes from hand-analysed datasets like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/outputs/datasets/#stcd&#34;&gt;STCD&lt;/a&gt;. This poster forms parrt of the wider &lt;a href=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/argument-cartography/&#34;&gt;Argument Cartography&lt;/a&gt; theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/img/dana_2017_eca.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SHORT ABSTRACT:&lt;/strong&gt; Argument diagramming has become a standard tool for visualising and exploring the structure of arguments and aiding in their analysis. The advent of digital technologies has lead to increasingly large datasets of analysed argument which can stretch the capabilities of traditional argument diagramming techniques and tools. We report on work to develop new argument visualisation techniques, computational implementations, that aim to support visualisation of arguments at scale, with ad hoc display and filtering of meta-data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/outputs/publications/#khartabil_2017_eca&#34;&gt;Bibliographic Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/assets/abstracts/khartabil_2017_eca.pdf&#34;&gt;Abstract (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.5146150.v1&#34;&gt;Poster (Figshare)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poster Presentation on Behaviour Change Arguments</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.06.23_eca_kate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 14:58:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.06.23_eca_kate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kate Pangbourne presented a poster at the Second European Conference on Argumentation based upon our joint research into behaviour change campaigns and its associated argumentative practises. Briefly, we are interested in the kinds of arguments that are used in behaviour change campaigns from the Sustainable Transport Domain. This builds on work in to the Sustainable Transport Communication Dataset (&lt;a href=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/outputs/datasets/#stcd&#34;&gt;STCD&lt;/a&gt;) theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/img/kate_2017_eca.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SHORT ABSTRACT:&lt;/strong&gt; Poor communication can undermine the preparatory work, conducted over long periods,  to construct favourable conditions for a major societal shift in behaviour. We examine the inferences that the designers of behaviour change interventions aim to produce in their target audience and the mismatch that can occur when interventions are deployed. Additionally we explore the related role and complicating factors that social media and digital technologies bring which can cause persuasive public communication to misfire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/outputs/publications/#pangbourne_2017_eca&#34;&gt;Bibliographic Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/assets/abstracts/pangbourne_2017_eca.pdf&#34;&gt;Abstract (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.5146153.v1&#34;&gt;Poster (Figshare)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ar:Ca:De Games in public</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.04.11_lovelace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 14:58:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.04.11_lovelace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Argument Card Debate (&lt;a href=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/arcade&#34;&gt;Ar:Ca:De&lt;/a&gt;) games we are building online and offline debate games that use &amp;lsquo;Argument Cards&amp;rsquo;, representations of arguments depicted using playing cards. The aim is to support people in engaging with both their own and other people&amp;rsquo;s arguments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/img/ama.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amantle Craviolatti recently attended the 2017 BCSWomen Lovelace Colloquium to present a poster and talk about her project with other Women in Computing. The poster can be &lt;a href=&#34;page/outputs/publications&#34;&gt;downloaded&lt;/a&gt; from our publications page&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Argumentation Research @ ENU</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.04.01_argumentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.04.01_argumentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Research into argumentation has become an increasingly hot research topic in AI in recent years. Argumentation Research at Edinburgh Napier University focusses on dialogue and strategy with forays into visualisation, tooling, datasets, and mining.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ADAMANT</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/adamant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/adamant/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;adamant |ˈadəm(ə)nt|&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;adjective&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;refusing to be persuaded or to change one&amp;rsquo;s mind: he is adamant that he is not going to resign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adamant is a DGDL runtime implementation for playing and managing dialogue games.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALIAS</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/alias/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/alias/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affiliate Members</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/people/affiliates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/people/affiliates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We like to work with various folk and are actively working with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.its.leeds.ac.uk/people/k.pangbourne&#34;&gt;Dr Kate Pangbourne&lt;/a&gt; (EPSRC Living with Environmental Change Fellow @ the University of Leeds)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www-users.cs.york.ac.uk/~tommy/&#34;&gt;Dr Tangming &amp;ldquo;Tommy&amp;rdquo; Yuan&lt;/a&gt; (University of York)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ar:Ca:De Games</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/arcade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/arcade/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArgDB</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/argdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/argdb/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Argument Cartograpy</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/argument-cartography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/argument-cartography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People have long visualised argument structure in order to better understand and analyse arguments. Initially this activity was paper based and lead to a variety of diagram styles, for example, Wigmore produced a large and complex visual language to describe legal argument whilst Toulmin produced a compact and popular style for describing individual arguments. Machine were used to support argument analysis and visualisation, leading to software such as Araucaria and Rationale, which define their own versions of the standard argument diagram familiar from basic logic. As the computational argument research community developed, the Argument Interchange Format (AIF) was developed to support the exchange of structured argument data between disparate tools. In parallel, a recent topic in argumentation that has been the subject of intense scrutiny is Argumentation Mining, the automatic recognition, extraction, and reconstruction of arguments from natural language resources. The ultimate goal promise of effective argumentation mining is for all arguments to be mined from all texts that contain them. This promises truly large datasets of arguments. Datasets at a scale which outrank all current visualisation efforts. The goal of argument cartography is to track the development of increasingly large-scale argument datasets and to develop suitable techniques for argument visualisation and exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DGDL</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/dgdl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/dgdl/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dana Khartabil</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/people/dana-khartabil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/people/dana-khartabil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dana is a Ph.D student funded under the fifty years of Edinburgh Napier scholarship scheme. Her research focusses on how to usefully visualise and consequently work with increasingly large argumentation datasets. Her research contributes to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/argument-cartography/&#34;&gt;Argument Cartography&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasets</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/outputs/datasets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/outputs/datasets/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;sustainable-transport-communications-dataset-stcd&#34;&gt;Sustainable Transport Communications Dataset (STCD)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;stcd&#34; style=&#34;visibility: hidden&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dataset is under continuous development to support research in behaviour change for sustainable transport and to provide an exemplar of practise in developing datasets to underpin reproducible &amp;amp; replicable Computer Science research. It has been reported upon in the following publications:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(2017) &lt;a href=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/outputs/publications/#pangbourne_2017_eca&#34;&gt;Abstract presented at the 2nd European Conference on Argumentaion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(2016) &lt;a href=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/outputs/publications/#wells_2016_sustainable&#34;&gt;Studies in Logic and Argumentation 62, Chapter 34&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(2015) &lt;a href=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/outputs/publications/#wells_2015_sustainable&#34;&gt;Abstract presented at the 1st European Conference on Argumentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dataset itself is stored in a Git repository and is available via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ARG-ENU/STCD&#34;&gt;STCD website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;climate-change-argument-dataset-ccad&#34;&gt;Climate Change Argument Dataset (CCAD)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;ccad&#34; style=&#34;visibility: hidden&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dataset has been developed to support research into visualisation of large-scale argument datasets. A goal in assembling this dataset was to develop a single, cohesive, large-scale dataset for a specific contentious real-world domain. The dataset is used in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/argument-cartography/&#34;&gt;Argument Cartography&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MonkeyPuzzle</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/monkeypuzzle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/project/monkeypuzzle/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There are two Monkeypuzzle tools; a rebranded version of Araucaria &amp;amp; a novel web interface. The aim is to provide argument analysis tools that are not dependent upon the cloud or other people&amp;rsquo;s computers so that, if you are a researcher or argument analyst you do not have to risk your workflow to the goodwill or longevity of third-party research organisations or commerical companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monkeypuzzle-web&#34;&gt;Monkeypuzzle (Web)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A free (GPL), open-source, web-based (HTML5, CSS, Javascript) argument analysis tool. This is available to use in three modes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a hosted web-service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a local, non-server based single-apge web-app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a browser-hosted, offline app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The source code for MonkeyPuzzle (web) is available from the project repository which also hosts the issue-tracker to support ongoing developement. There is also a live, hosted version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monkeypuzzle-desktop&#34;&gt;Monkeypuzzle (Desktop)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Araucaria was one of the first argument analysis tools, developed in 2001 at the University of Dundee. Unfortunately Arauacaria was not updated for many years, partly due to researchers moving to newer tools. However, Araucaria was the only GPL-licensed, pure argument analysis toolwhich meant that as other tools became &amp;ldquo;online only&amp;rdquo; or subscription based, Araucaria remained the only free, source-inclusive, argument analysis tool that analysts could run privately on their own machine. For many users, being able to perform private analyses of argumentation resources, for example, within research or legal argumentation, is critical, and externally hosted web-services are not an acceptable substitute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, Araucaria was adopted under it&amp;rsquo;s GPL license, the code was added to a modern source-control repository, and regular builds were created to ensure that the tool will run under modern Java virtual machines. To celebrate this new lease of life, Araucaria was rebranded to Monkeypuzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Past Members</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/people/past/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/page/people/past/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes folk stay for a little while then move on to better things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adam Kisala&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amantle Craviolatti&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John Douglas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roberto Franesco La Greca&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hristo Meshinski&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>